# Himanshu Soni

# Full Stack Developer

\$\&\ +91-8871778862\$

himanshua790@gmail.com

in @himanshuu-soni

(2) @himanshua790

@code-08

himanshusoni.tech

## Resume Summary

Entrepreneurial spirit and a passion for learning and growth. I am able to work independently with a growth mindset, and I have excellent problem-solving skills. I have a can-do attitude and am not afraid to take risks. Additionally, I am a collaborative team player with strong communication and good management skills. Experienced in fast-paced startup environments.

## Work Experience

## Fuel Growth (Integrations)

Software Developer Part-Time

08/2023 - 10/2023

- Provided seamless integration support for Shopify, Facebook, TikTok integration.
- Collaborated with the fuelgrowth ai team to implement data-driven strategies for ecommerce optimization.

#### RoaDo

Software Developer Full-Time

01/2022 - 07/2023

- Developed geofencing feature with GPS for fleet tracking and notifications, improving fleet tracking accuracy by 20%.
- Built Dealer module to facilitate communication between industries.
- Restructured application to support multiple sources and destinations and added multilevel filters.
- Revamped the UI and functionality of the assignment module, resulting in a significant 62% improvement in user experience.
- Tech: MongoDB, React.js, Node.js, Express.js, GraphQL, TypeScript, Redis, AWS S3, Redux, PWA, Material UI.

#### Autowriter.ai (Product Description Generator)

Full-Stack Developer Self-Employed

05/2021 - 01/2022

- Developed Shopify application that generated product descriptions.
- Maintained and improved GPT-3 APIs for better results.
- Collaborated with the team to troubleshoot and debug issues.
- Tech: JavaScript, Redux, Next.js, Polaris, OAuth, Shopify App-Bridge, Express, GraphQL, RabbitMQ.

#### The Kabadiwala

Python Developer Internship

01/2021 - 05/2021

- Developed a constrained vehicle routing solution that improved efficiency by 32% over manual routing.
- Established a data pipeline to validate customer addresses.
- Developed dashboards and reports to track key performance indicators.
- Tech: Google OR-Tools, Scripting, Python, SQL, Data Scraping, MS-Excel, Git, HTML, CSS.

# Project

#### Rishihood University - Swami Vivekananda Chatbot

- Designed, developed, and deployed an innovative AI-powered platform, <u>vivekananda.ai</u>, to revolutionize book research and interaction.
- Leveraged modern technologies including Langchain, React.js, and Next.js to create a dynamic and user-friendly interface.
- Implemented an intelligent search system that provides contextually relevant answers from book content, resulting in enriched user interactions.
- Quantified impact: Increased user engagement by 40%.
- Media Coverage: LinkedIn, Twitter.

### Education

Bachelor of Technology in Electronics and Communications Medi-Caps University, Indore Specialization in Computer Technologies. 2016-2020

CGPA: 7.48/10

#### Skills

## Frontend Technologies

• Markup & Styling: HTML, CSS, Markdown, SASS/SCSS

• Scripting: JavaScript, TypeScript

• Frameworks: Next.js, React.js, Three.js, Tailwind CSS, Material-UI

• Code Quality: ESLint, Prettier

• Web Technologies: Web Components, Service Workers

• Testing: Puppeteer, Jest

#### **Backend Technologies**

• Core: Node.js, Python

Frameworks: Express, DjangoOthers: Bash, JWT, OAuth

• Testing & Debugging: Jest, Visual Studio

• Message Broker: RabbitMQ

#### **Databases**

• SQL: MySQL, PostgreSQL

NoSQL: MongoDBInMemory: Redis

#### **Cloud Platforms**

• AWS: Lambda, S3, API Gateway, EC2, Elastic IP

• Google Cloud Platform: OAuth2, Gmail API

#### Interests

Passionate about web development and design, ecommerce, and using augmented reality to create immersive shopping experiences. Also, deeply interested in building scalable applications with the aim of serving millions of users. My goal is to develop full-fledged, highly scalable applications that can meet the demands of a large user base.